International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 2126 Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 2126 Records.
undated, 1958-1961.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 2126 (Windsor Locks, Conn.)
.5 linear feet.
MSS20000121
History
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 2126, represented the employees of Flight Enterprises, Inc., and International Aircraft Services, Inc., located at Bradley Field in Windsor Locks, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection covers the period 1958 through 1961, although the majority of the materials are dated 1959-1960. The Lodge Records include correspondence, by-laws, agreements, minutes and financial records.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut labor records. In particular, Archives and Special Collections holds the records of several other IAMAW Lodges also located in Connecticut. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Flight Enterprises, Inc.; International Aircraft Services, Inc.; Collective labor agreements—Aircraft industry.; Collective labor agreements—Connecticut.; Independent unions—Connecticut.; Aerospace industries—Employees—Labor unions—Connecticut.; Machinists—Labor unions—Connecticut.; Aircraft industry—Employees—Labor unions—Connecticut.; Aircraft industry—Connecticut.; Aircraft industry workers—Connecticut.; Aerospace industries—Connecticut.; Connecticut—Business, industries, and trades—Aircraft.; Connecticut— Business, industries, and trades—Aerospace.; Windsor Locks (Conn.)—Business, industries, and trades—Aircraft.; Windsor Locks (Conn.)—Business, industries, and trades—Aerospace.; Connecticut—Labor—Trade-unions.; Windsor Locks (Conn.)—Labor—Trade-unions.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Occupations:
Labor union.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Records, undated, 1958-1961
  - Agreement—Flight Enterprises, Inc., 1958-1960 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - By-laws, undated, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1959-1961 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1959-1961 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Financial Records
    - Audit Reports and monthly statements, 1959-1960 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Monthly Report (Grand Lodge), 1959-1960 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Forms, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Membership and tax report summary, 1958-1960 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Officers, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Selection of Arbitrators, 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 10)